hello everyone
大家好
hello hello welcome to another Jakarta
你好，你好，欢迎来到另一个雅加达
tech talks we have today Sebastian -
塞巴斯蒂安今天举行的技术讲座-
nari here with us and apologies to
纳里在这里与我们道歉
everyone for a little bit of the delay
每个人都有一点点延迟
here it is the technology of course that
这当然是技术
caused the problems so it's not us never
造成了问题，所以这不是我们永远不会
us so I'll just write away handed over
我们，所以我就把写完的东西交出去
to Sebastian and give him a chance to
给塞巴斯蒂安，让他有机会
get going with cabin erik kubernetes and
开始与机舱erik kubernetes和
east EO for jakarta he developers thank
开发人员感谢雅加达东部EO
Sebastian for joining and yeah take it
塞巴斯蒂安加入，是的
over alright yeah thanks a lot for the
是的，非常感谢
introduction and hi from my side my
介绍，从我身边我很高兴
mommy Sebastian - nur and welcome to
妈妈塞巴斯蒂安-努尔，欢迎来到
this talk kubernetes and sto for Jakarta
这次的kubernetes和sto为雅加达
EE developers so about myself Bastian -
EE开发人员对我自己的了解Bastian-
na born and raised in Munich Germany and
na在德国慕尼黑出生和长大，
I am a developer advocate for IBM and I
我是IBM的开发人员拥护者，我
have a big like Java background and
具有类似Java的背景，并且
enterprise software at backgrounds in
后台的企业软件
general and today I want to show you a
一般，今天我想向您展示
few things on while why we Java EE or
为什么我们使用Java EE或
jacquard EE developers should be
提花EE开发人员应
interested in cloud native technologies
对云原生技术感兴趣
specifically kubernetes initio and what
特别是kubernetes initio和什么
that is so we gonna see a little bit
所以我们会看到一点
about that and first of all I want to
关于这一点，首先我想
introduce an example microservice
介绍一个示例微服务
quote-unquote example application or
quote-unquote示例应用程序或
actually actually two applications
实际上两个应用
because one application is boring and we
因为一个应用程序很无聊，我们
want to have some communication
想要沟通
specifically with container
特别是与容器
orchestration and service measures and
编排和服务措施以及
all that and I like coffee
所有这些，我喜欢咖啡
so I'm gonna have an enterprise Java and
所以我要有一个企业Java
enterprise coffee example so what that
企业咖啡的例子
is we're gonna have a coffee shop an
我们要去咖啡厅吗
example of enterprise coffee with two
两个企业咖啡的例子
applications - micro servers if if you
应用程序-如果您使用微型服务器
want and one is called coffee shop and
想要，一个叫做咖啡店，
the other one is called barista
另一个叫做咖啡师
means if we want to order some coffee as
表示如果我们要点咖啡
a developer we go to the coffee shop as
一个开发商，我们去咖啡店
a client and make some coffee order and
客户并点咖啡订单，
then for our for the sake of the example
然后为了我们的例子
we have a synchronous communication from
我们有一个来自
the coffee shop to the barista back-end
咖啡店到咖啡师的后端
so it works a little bit like this we
所以它有点像我们
have a request coming in or the coffee
有要求进来或喝咖啡
that could be an HTTP endpoint or
可能是HTTP端点或
whatever boundary we we offer and that
无论我们提供什么边界，
then does a synchronous requests to the
然后向
barista back-end so we're gonna have or
咖啡师后端，所以我们要拥有或
the coffee and then something like start
咖啡，然后像开始
a coffee brewing process and order that
咖啡冲泡过程和命令
at the barista back-end system ok so
在咖啡师后端系统还可以
finally is go to the code enough slides
终于是去了足够的代码幻灯片
so what I have is actually two
所以我实际上只有两个
enterprise applications that use two
使用两个的企业应用程序
Java EE api's or jacquard EE api's and
Java EE api或提花EE api和
as in the future and also micro profile
和将来一样
I'm gonna show a little bit of that in a
我将在其中展示一点
second so one is called coffee shop and
第二个叫做咖啡店
the other one is called barista so these
另一个叫做咖啡师，所以这些
are Java Enterprise projects we're gonna
是我们要开发的Java Enterprise项目
have the Java EE 8 API that is provided
具有提供的Java EE 8 API
a little bit more about that in a second
再过一会儿
and just because I'm brave I use JDK 11
只是因为我很勇敢，所以我使用JDK 11
already on an application server I use
已经在我使用的应用程序服务器上
open Liberty and let me quickly have
打开自由，让我快速拥有
some quick walkthrough to the code and
一些快速的代码演练，以及
then we're gonna deploy that so today
那我们今天要部署
it's a little bit less about only Java
仅Java少一点
EE or to card EE api's it's a lot more
EE或卡片EE API的功能更多
about the cloud native environment so we
关于云原生环境，所以我们
quickly gonna deploy that using docker
快速使用docker进行部署
containers and of course kubernetes
容器，当然还有kubernetes
clusters and sto service meshes so how
集群和存储服务网格，如何
that works this order coffee process is
适用于此订单咖啡过程的是
let's have a look at there is one
让我们看一看
resource that is called ortus
称为ortus的资源
so our order coffee boundary is gonna be
所以我们的订单咖啡边界将是
an entity HTTP endpoint that we
我们的实体HTTP端点
implement using jax-rs so as Enterprise
使用jax-rs来实现，例如Enterprise
developers we're probably familiar with
我们可能熟悉的开发人员
jax-rs so we have something like at path
jax-rs，所以我们在路径上有类似的东西
or this annotation on a class that makes
或在使
us that gives us a jak source resource
给我们带来了麻烦的我们
here and then we have something like
在这里，然后我们有像
give us the orders in
给我们下订单
location Jason format and also takes
位置Jason格式，也需要
some order order some coffee or we can
点些命令点咖啡，或者我们可以
provide a plane a job or object the type
提供飞机工作或物体的类型
Java class coffee order so that means we
Java类咖啡订单，这意味着我们
gonna post a specific JSON object that
将发布一个特定的JSON对象
represents a coffee order here and then
代表这里的咖啡订单
let's quickly walk around walk through
让我们快速走来走去
this code we're gonna have a coffee shop
这个代码我们要去咖啡店
or the coffee component here another
或这里的咖啡成分
class where we have the business logic
我们拥有业务逻辑的课程
of ordering a coffee so if we have a
点一杯咖啡，如果我们有一个
look at the diagram while ultimately we
看图，最终我们
want to call that second system we're
想调用第二个系统
gonna have a synchronous requests to the
将会有一个同步请求
barista system that means we kind of
咖啡师系统，这意味着我们有点
have some client call that might be HTTP
有一些可能是HTTP的客户端调用
in that case as well this is what I have
在这种情况下，这就是我所拥有的
within another component that is called
在另一个称为
barista that is actually an HTTP client
实际上是HTTP客户端的咖啡师
and in my case I use while jax-rs on the
在我的情况下，我在
client side to connect to that back-end
客户端连接到该后端
as well all right and then this means
好吧，那么这意味着
well we're gonna create a request here
好，我们要在这里创建一个请求
and we're going to use the jax-ur as
我们将使用jax-ur作为
client API to well make an HTTP put
客户端API可以很好地进行HTTP放置
request to to the to the other resource
请求到其他资源
alright that's enough for the code level
好了，对于代码级别来说足够了
on the Java EE api's now if we want to
如果我们想在Java EE api上
run that example in a cloud native
在本机云中运行该示例
setting first of all what we might have
首先设定我们可能拥有的
is well we want to run that in a docker
很好，我们想在docker中运行它
container so that means we need a docker
容器，这意味着我们需要一个码头工人
image that means we need some darker
这意味着我们需要更暗的图像
files for example so this is the docker
例如文件，所以这是码头工人
file for a coffee shop application and
申请咖啡店申请，以及
in jacquard ee that is actually very
在提花ee中，实际上非常
simple to do because if we use thin
容易做，因为如果我们使用薄
deployment artifacts most of it what we
部署工件大部分是我们
need is actually done in our base image
需求实际上是在我们的基础映像中完成的
so we can provide many images and create
因此我们可以提供许多图像并创建
images like how we want them I use an
像我们想要的图像一样，我使用
image that contains the Open Liberty
包含开放自由的图像
application server plus JDK 11 plus some
应用服务器加上JDK 11加上一些
extra stuff that I will show in a second
额外的东西，我将在一秒钟内显示
then we will add some of thin
然后我们将添加一些薄
configuration also show more of that in
配置还显示了更多内容
a second and then actually what the only
一秒钟，然后实际上只有什么
thing we're really adding during
我们真正在添加的东西
development
发展
the waffle is our deployment artifact
华夫饼是我们的部署工件
our coffee shop war that resides inside
我们内部的咖啡店大战
target if we built that using maven
目标，如果我们使用Maven构建
and that's pretty much it so let's
差不多就是这样，让我们
quickly demo that we're gonna have maven
快速演示我们将要行家
to build a project maiden clean package
建立一个项目的初次清洁包装
and then we're gonna have something like
然后我们会有类似的东西
a darker build to build our our image in
更黑暗的构建来建立我们的形象
a specific tack and that builds it and
一个具体的办法，并建立它和
also again this is actually super fast
同样，这实际上是超级快
because we're only using caches for the
因为我们仅将缓存用于
base image layers thanks to the
基本图像层归功于
copy-on-write file system of a docker
Docker的写时复制文件系统
and then we have a thin deployment
然后我们进行精简部署
artifact that is actually tiny if we use
如果我们使用的话，它实际上很小
that approach with only provided
该方法仅提供
dependencies so that's 20 kilobyte and
依赖关系，所以是20 KB，
then we build built this and then we're
然后我们建立建立这个，然后我们
done all right the same is actually true
没事没事，实际上是对的
for the barista system so the barista
对于咖啡师系统，所以咖啡师
that's even more simple what I'm gonna
那我要变得更简单
do here and I'm talk a little bit about
在这里做，我谈论一些
about that later I here I use only micro
关于那以后我在这里我只用微
profile dependencies that means in this
配置文件依赖关系
case I actually only use Jack's arrests
如果我实际上只用杰克的逮捕
and CDI and think JSONP for that example
和CDI，并以JSONP为例
for the barista so it's even sufficient
对于咖啡师来说就足够了
to use that dependency anyway if I use
无论如何如果我使用
an application server that also supports
也支持的应用程序服务器
micro profile or you know combinations
微观轮廓或您知道组合
of the api's depending what you need in
的api取决于您所需要的
your project that is possible as well so
您的项目也是可能的
the stalker file here for our barista
我们咖啡师的缠扰者档案
application looks very similar we have
应用程序看起来非常相似
while our deployment artifact barista
而我们的部署工件咖啡师
odwar and the same thing here as well
odwar和这里的同一件事
alright that's enough of docker assume
好了，Docker假设就足够了
we know about that already so let's go
我们已经知道了，所以让我们开始吧
into the kubernetes world a little bit
进入kubernetes世界
so if we build that one I just showed
因此，如果我们建立一个我刚刚展示的
you
您
well we could deploy that locally but
好吧，我们可以在本地部署
that's kind of boring actually because
这有点无聊，实际上是因为
we want to run this in a cloud native
我们想在本机云中运行
setting in a kubernetes cluster so we
在kubernetes集群中设置
could run our docker containers but now
可以运行我们的docker容器，但是现在
well I want to have an approach where I
好吧，我想有一种方法
manage some containers and this is
管理一些容器，这是
actually where kubernetes comes into
kubernetes真正进入的地方
play
玩
why kubernetes well kubernetes is so
为什么kubernetes很好kubernetes是如此
called
叫
container orchestration well that means
容器编排很好，这意味着
in orchestrates containers as easy as it
在容器中精心安排
sounds so that means if we have a
听起来就意味着如果我们有一个
production setting or a more
生产设置或更多
sophisticated environment where we have
我们拥有的复杂环境
multiple nodes actually and not just one
实际上有多个节点，而不仅仅是一个
running laptop or something then it
运行笔记本电脑之类的东西
becomes quite complex quite easily how
很容易变得很复杂
to well run all of that in production
在生产中很好地运行所有这些
right we need to manage networks we need
对，我们需要管理所需的网络
to set up ports and forward them and so
设置端口并转发它们等等
on and so forth
依此类推
we need to orchestrate where our
我们需要协调我们的位置
individual containers actually run and
各个容器实际运行并
so on and so forth so this is actually
依此类推，所以这实际上是
already provided by the technology in a
该技术已经在
somewhat production-ready way and that
有点准备生产的方式
means we can well deploy that so how do
意味着我们可以很好地部署它，那么该怎么做
we get a kubernetes cluster there are
我们有一个kubernetes集群
many many ways how to do that for
有很多方法可以做到这一点
example we could set up a mini cube on
例如我们可以在
our running laptop or we could go to the
我们正在运行的笔记本电脑，或者我们可以去
cloud for a managed environment I use
我使用的用于托管环境的云
the IBM cloud that is called IKS for
被称为IKS的IBM云
manage kubernetes
管理kubernetes
and this is what I'm going to use here
这就是我要在这里使用的
so we have the cube control command line
所以我们有了多维数据集控制命令行
available for while accessing kubernetes
可用于访问kubernetes
and then we can do something like clip
然后我们可以像剪辑一样
control give us the services that are
控制为我们提供的服务
running or give us the running part and
运行或给我们运行部分
this means this is currently empty so
这意味着当前是空的，所以
what is that a service or a pod so how
那是什么服务或吊舱，如何
our application looks like in a
我们的应用程序看起来像
container orchestration is something
容器编排是什么
similar to follows we're gonna have well
类似于以下内容，我们会很好
a part and a so-called service so what
零件和所谓的服务
is that a service is a logical
服务是合乎逻辑的
abstraction over an application or over
应用程序或应用程序之上的抽象
a micro service in in our case that
在我们的案例中，微服务
means if we have a coffee shop
表示如果我们有咖啡店
application the application itself that
应用程序本身
will be a service that might be backed
将是可能支持的服务
by multiple running instances so if we
被多个正在运行的实例
gonna if you want to have multiple
如果你想拥有多个
running application servers or
运行应用程序服务器或
containers or runtimes that all provide
都提供的容器或运行时
the same functionality that would be one
相同的功能
service for the coffee shop implemented
实施咖啡店服务
by multiple running parts a pod is an
通过多个运行部分，吊舱是
atomic workload in communities so that
社区中的原子工作量，以便
means we have one or more running parts
表示我们有一个或多个运行部件
and
和
two of them contain a container a dock
其中两个包含一个集装箱，一个码头
docker container for example and this is
例如docker容器，这是
provided by the coffee shop service and
咖啡厅提供的服务和
now if we want to access an order some
现在，如果我们要访问某个订单
coffee we're going to access that coffee
咖啡，我们将要访问该咖啡
shop service and end up at one running
商店服务并最终一次运行
instance here and then in the same way
在这里实例，然后以相同的方式
if they're running container if our
如果他们在运行容器，如果我们
application wants to access another
应用程序想要访问另一个
application for example the barista it
应用程序，例如咖啡师吧
accesses the service and ends up at one
访问该服务并最终合而为一
of the running pods and well the same
运转的豆荚，和相同
way back so let me quickly show you some
往回走，让我快速向您展示一些
llamo code yay everybody loves em oh so
llamo代码yay每个人都喜欢em哦，所以
this is modern way I guess how to define
这是我想如何定义的现代方式
cloud native resources
云原生资源
we're gonna have some llamo definitions
我们将有一些llamo定义
for a service and a deployment well now
现在可以很好地进行服务和部署
hold on what is a deployment
坚持什么是部署
well a deployment is a way how to manage
部署是一种管理方式
parts in a more sophisticated ways of
零件以更复杂的方式
for example if we say we have a running
例如，如果我们说我们正在跑步
instance a running container and now we
实例一个正在运行的容器，现在我们
want to actually deploy a new version or
想要实际部署新版本或
scale up or down that means we instead
放大或缩小表示我们改为
of creating a part directly we actually
直接创建零件的过程
create a resource that manages parts for
创建用于管理零件的资源
us and this is the deployment and we can
我们，这就是部署，我们可以
say now please provide 1:1 replica one
现在说请提供1：1副本
part of the following specification for
以下规范的一部分
example with the following docker image
以下docker镜像的示例
that we just built and and run that and
我们刚刚建立并运行
what is up here is the service
这里是服务
definition so this is just defining a
定义，所以这只是定义一个
name coffee shop that's the name of the
给咖啡店起个名字
service and it's gonna forward well that
服务，它将向前发展
port 90-80 that's the default port for
端口90-80是默认端口
open Liberty to following parts that are
向以下部分开放自由
well that contain this label app coffee
以及包含此标签的应用程序咖啡
shop so I might have multiple parts that
店，所以我可能有多个部分
back my coffee shop service and that all
支持我的咖啡店服务，这一切
will are selected then from the service
将从服务中选择
and the service does a load balancing or
该服务进行负载平衡或
load distribution to all the running
负载分配到所有正在运行的
instances there all right the barista
实例在那里，咖啡师
one looks very similar we have a barista
一个看起来很相似，我们有一个咖啡师
service here with a named barista and
服务在这里与一个命名的咖啡师和
also of course a deployment these two
当然也部署这两个
applications again totally isolated
应用程序再次完全隔离
alright now let's do this
好吧，现在让我们这样做
let's finally deploy something we're
让我们最后部署一些我们正在
gonna use Q control apply command to
将使用Q控制apply命令来
well apply these resources that we have
好好运用我们拥有的这些资源
so we're gonna we can throw in a whole
所以我们要把整个
folder actually off the coffee shop and
文件夹实际上在咖啡店外
the barista and then it's gonna create
咖啡师，然后它将创建
all the resources for us the reason why
所有资源对我们来说是为什么
this is called applied and this is
这被称为应用，这是
actually a nice story we can say oh if I
其实是一个很好的故事，我们可以说哦，如果我
reapply that it actually doesn't hurt
重新申请它实际上没有伤害
anything these resources are applied or
这些资源的任何应用或
changed or created depending on the
更改或创建，具体取决于
current status of the cluster so if
集群的当前状态，如果
that's already existing on the cluster
在集群中已经存在
that doesn't matter
没关系
and now if I ask for the services that
现在，如果我要服务
are in my cluster Q control that
在我的集群Q控件中
services I'll see a coffee shop and a
服务，我会看到一家咖啡店和一家
barista service and cute control get
咖啡师服务和可爱的控制得到
pods give me well the running gives me
豆荚给我很好，跑步给了我
the running pots and for coffee shop and
跑步壶和咖啡厅，以及
for a barista alright that's nice so now
对于咖啡师来说还不错，所以现在
we're gonna access that and I get my
我们将访问它，我得到我的
cluster IP in my running cluster I say
我说我正在运行的群集中的群集IP
coffee shop resources orders for example
例如咖啡店资源订单
that gives me the coffee orders that is
这给了我咖啡订单
well empty empty JSON array because
空JSON空数组，因为
there's no there are no orders in the
那里没有订单
system so this corresponds to what you
系统，所以这对应于您
just saw in the orders resource this is
刚刚在订单资源中看到的是
now deployed here that is the coffee
现在部署在这里的就是咖啡
shop application I accessed while the IP
IP时访问的商店应用程序
of the cluster coffee shop that is the
集群咖啡店的
context path of my application and the
我的应用程序的上下文路径和
resources is actually all the name of my
资源实际上就是我所有的名字
jax-rs application here and then we end
jax-rs应用程序在这里，然后我们结束
up at the orders resource alright and we
在订单资源上，我们
get the orders and the system that's in
获取订单和其中的系统
memory actually for default for example
例如，实际上默认的内存
cases so there's nothing here there is
案例，所以这里什么都没有
no coffee yet but let's change this
还没有咖啡，但让我们改变一下
we're gonna create some coffee so that
我们要煮些咖啡，以便
means I need to post some JSON to this
意味着我需要向此发布一些JSON
resource right gonna create a post
正确的资源将创建一个帖子
request on using kernel for example
要求使用内核
where we're going to post some
我们将在其中发布一些
application JSON content
应用程序JSON内容
type let's have a look at how the coffee
键入，让我们来看看咖啡如何
or it actually looks like the coffee
或实际上看起来像咖啡
order has a bunch of things and
订单有一堆东西，
especially a coffee type but we want to
特别是咖啡类型，但我们想
provide that means while espresso or
提供意式浓缩咖啡或
latte or whatever we're gonna we want to
拿铁咖啡或我们想要的任何东西
drink let's say we would like to have an
喝酒吧，我们想喝一杯
espresso here and we're gonna create
这里的意式浓缩咖啡，我们将创造
that and hopefully well that works 201
那并希望它能正常工作201
created so that has been created and
已创建，因此已创建并
hopefully well yeah that's already also
希望很好，是的
in the system
在系统中
alright that's good news so apparently
好吧，这显然是个好消息
we now have some coffee
我们现在喝咖啡
in our systems of coffee order at least
至少在我们的咖啡订购系统中
alright so one thing that you might have
好了，所以你可能有一件事
noticed if you look at how the barista
注意到，如果您看看咖啡师
service is being accessed in our coffee
我们的咖啡正在提供服务
shop application if you paid attention
如果您关注商店申请
in our httpclient how we connected to
在我们的httpclient中我们如何连接到
the other application that's already
另一个已经存在的应用程序
very interesting is we did not configure
非常有趣的是我们没有配置
any IP address or any dns resolution
任何IP地址或任何DNS解析
something like that for the DM for the
像这样的DM
individual individual environments that
个体个体环境
we might have we only specified barista
我们可能只指定了咖啡师
which is actually very nice story for us
对我们来说这实际上是一个很好的故事
because this enables us to well
因为这使我们能够
hard-code even that URL and to get rid
甚至对该URL进行硬编码并摆脱
of of environment specific configuration
特定于环境的配置
so how does that work
那如何运作
kubernetes per default does where is my
每个默认的kubernetes都在哪里
resource does the dns resolution a
DNS解析资源
cluster internal DNS resolution for all
所有群集的内部DNS解析
the service names so that means because
服务名称，因此意味着
of that name barista we can actually
这个名字的咖啡师，我们实际上可以
access barista to a hostname lookup in
将咖啡师访问主机名查找
that internally in that namespace in the
在内部的名称空间中
cluster and end up at one of the running
集群并最终在运行之一
instances of our barista application
咖啡师应用程序的实例
which is very nice because then we don't
这非常好，因为那时我们不
have to configure an ax p address or a
必须配置一个ax p地址或一个
dns name for for example test system dot
DNS名称，例如测试系统点
barista example corporation and so on
咖啡师示例公司等
and so forth so this makes it very easy
等等，这使得它非常容易
for us to get rid of configuration here
让我们在这里摆脱配置
so that's about the kubernetes here and
这是关于这里的kubernetes和
then apparently well that works so as we
那么显然很好，因为我们
saw this already gives us that running
看到这已经给了我们跑步
application in well production in a
在某油井生产中的应用
production setting so a few more things
生产设置，还有更多事情
when it comes to configuration for
当涉及到配置
example and configuration is a very
示例和配置是一个非常
interesting part especially if we talk
有趣的部分，特别是如果我们谈论
about 12:12 factor applications so 12
大约12:12因数应用，所以12
factors are well interesting aspects
因素是有趣的方面
that have been set up in this initiative
在该计划中已经建立的
here you might have a look at and
在这里你可以看看
especially if we build our enterprise
特别是如果我们建立我们的企业
applications using or cloud native
使用或Cloud Native的应用程序
technologies using containers and
使用容器和技术
container orchestration you might have a
容器编排，您可能会有
look that pretty much all of these
看起来几乎所有这些
factors are then already applied for
因素已经申请
example configuration that means get rid
意味着摆脱的示例配置
of the configuration on the application
应用程序上的配置
level and rather try to inject it from
水平，而是尝试从
outside of the application from the
在应用程序之外
environment that means we don't want to
这意味着我们不想
configure which barista back-end
配置哪个咖啡师后端
application we use while we make that
我们在制作时使用的应用程序
part of the environment by using a DNS
使用DNS的一部分环境
resolution or in other words if we have
分辨率或换句话说，如果我们有
to change a replication if for some
更改复制，如果有的话
reason it has to behave differently in
为什么它必须表现不同
different environments then we do not
不同的环境，那么我们就不
want to build multiple running multiple
要建立多个运行多个
binaries actually no we want to build
二进制文件实际上不，我们要构建
one in the same binary once and provided
一次使用同一二进制文件提供
everywhere and well inject potential
遍地开花，潜力无限
differences from the outside
与外界的差异
why because of reliability and because
为什么因为可靠性，又因为
of testing that means in our continuous
测试意味着我们不断
delivery pipeline we want to build our
我们想要建立我们的交付管道
image and binary once and use that
映像和二进制一次并使用
binary in each and every stage and test
在每个阶段和测试中都是二进制的
it so then we can be sure that later on
因此，我们可以确定以后
it will work because we always test the
它会起作用，因为我们始终会测试
same thing so this is one thing that I
同一件事，所以这是我的一件事
already use here in especially the
已经在这里使用，特别是
coffee shop class here if you and you
如果你和你在这里喝咖啡
maybe saw it already I have a location
也许已经看到了我的位置
here that is actually being injected or
这实际上是在注入或
being
存在
figure that is well when my coffee is
当我喝咖啡的时候这个数字很好
being brewed I would say so if we have
酿造我会说，如果我们有
our coffee order and if for example we
我们的咖啡订单，例如
access that that order here then we
在这里访问该订单，然后我们
might see well we have also a location
可能会很好，我们也有一个位置
available default that's it's going to
可用的默认值是
brood on Java so the island so in this
在Java上繁衍，所以在这个岛上
case where does that come from we can
这种情况是从哪里来的
configure actually this brew location
实际上配置此酿造位置
and in this way we're gonna use micro
这样我们将使用微型
profile config so actually if you use an
配置文件配置，所以实际上，如果您使用
application runtime that supports the
支持
Java EE or Jakarta EE standards as well
以及Java EE或Jakarta EE标准
as micro profile projects for example
例如，作为微型配置文件项目
micah profile config for configuration
micah配置文件配置
you can actually use and mix and match
您可以实际使用和混合搭配
all the api's that are part of while
同时存在的所有api
Enterprise Java that are part of Java EE
属于Java EE的企业Java
slash micro profile so why do I want to
大幅削减微轮廓，为什么我要
use this well I want to configure a
用这个好我想配置一个
configure my application here in a
在这里配置我的应用程序
somewhat cloud native way that means I
有点云原生的方式，这意味着我
don't want to change my application here
不想在这里更改我的应用程序
but provide the configuration from the
但从
outside in this case it's actually
在这种情况下，实际上
provided by an environment variable well
由环境变量很好地提供
how do you know this there are multiple
你怎么知道这有多个
default config sources in micro profile
微型配置文件中的默认配置源
available that means this lookup key
可用，表示此查找键
location here might be injected from for
可能是从这里注入的位置
example the environment variables of my
我的环境变量示例
running container of my system so that
运行我的系统的容器，以便
is being available out of the box and
开箱即用
then I can provide this location here
那我可以在这里提供这个位置
the default that's being called home and
默认被称为home和
I have a few locations available and to
我有几个可用的位置
look up well the default is home or
查找很好，默认为home或
unless it's provided a well in an
除非它在
environment variable so where does it
环境变量，它在哪里
come from specifically in my deployment
来自我的部署中
you probably already saw that actually
你可能已经看到了
I'm going to set an environment variable
我要设置一个环境变量
location so that is a kubernetes
位置，所以这是一个kubernetes
specific configuration it's very similar
具体配置非常相似
to a docker run with an environment
到在环境中运行的docker
variable a parameter it actually does
变量实际执行的参数
that under the hood and sets this
在引擎盖下设置
environment variable well with a
环境变量很好
specific value so you can either set a
特定值，因此您可以设置一个
value
值
directly for example Java or say the
直接例如Java或说
value actually comes from a config map
值实际上来自配置映射
or another configuration store so a
或其他配置存储，因此
config map is another type in Cuban
配置映射是古巴语中的另一种类型
Aires where I can actually configure
我可以实际配置的Aires
something in an environment and then
在环境中然后
later on what I actually want to achieve
稍后我真正想要实现的
here is to say well in this running
这是说在这次跑步中很好
deployment I want to configure it using
部署我想使用配置
that environment config map
该环境配置图
configuration or I'm gonna actually
配置，否则我实际上
outsource this snippet put it into a
将此代码片段外包
different file for a different
不同的文件
environment from a test environment for
测试环境中的环境
production environment and I'm gonna
生产环境，我要
overwrite that using a different
用不同的方式覆盖
location
位置
and then well I can reconfigure my
然后我可以重新配置我的
application without actually changing
无需实际更改的应用程序
the image so this is very nice and this
图像，所以这是非常好的，这
well implements 12 this approach of the
很好地实施12这种方法
12 factors here all right
这里有12个因素
that's about to say about the 12 factors
即将要讲的12个因素
now if we have a look at that this
现在，如果我们看看这个
already runs in production this example
已经在生产中运行此示例
but it's certainly not well production
但是生产肯定不好
ready for example it's lacking a few
准备好了，例如缺少
concerns and now this is where service
关注，现在这是服务的地方
meshes or sto come into play and
网格或sto起作用
especially if we think about well the
特别是如果我们考虑得好
part observability what is going on
部分可观察性发生了什么
inside our application then we might not
在我们的应用程序中，那么我们可能不会
well see or know everything here so that
好在这里看到或知道一切，以便
means just because our resource our
只是因为我们的资源
request has been created here and just
请求已在此处创建，只是
because our diagram says that apparently
因为我们的图表显然表明
the barista application is being called
咖啡师应用程序被调用
we actually have no clue what's going on
我们实际上不知道发生了什么
we don't really see into the system so
我们并没有真正进入系统
we lack observability here but
我们这里缺乏可观察性，但是
thankfully the cluster that I have here
幸好我在这里有集群
is not only a kubernetes cluster but is
不仅是kubernetes集群，而且
in fact an sto cluster and SDO is a
实际上，一个sto集群和SDO是一个
service mesh technology that well is
很好的服务网格技术
probably the most widely used service
可能是使用最广泛的服务
mesh technology out there and it heavily
网格技术在那里，它沉重
builds upon kubernetes or supports
基于kubernetes或支持
kubernetes and works very well together
kubernetes并能很好地协同工作
and what is the service mesh well a
什么是服务网格
service mesh is a mesh
服务网格是一个网格
of interconnected micro service
互连微服务
deployments where we actually can add
我们实际上可以添加的部署
some concerns to each and every
每个人都有一些担忧
application without changing the
无需更改应用程序
applications directly but adding
直接添加应用程序
concerns from the outside in a somewhat
来自外部的担忧
transparent way concerns suggest
透明的方式表示关注
observability or resiliency or more
可观察性或弹性或更高
advanced traffic management and let's
先进的交通管理，让我们
start with observability here actually
从这里的可观察性开始
there is one way let's have a look at
有一种方法让我们看一下
the it's at work again my secret port
它又在工作我的秘密港口
forwarding said that this works
转发说这有效
this is graph on ax what is graph Anna
这是斧头上的图什么是图安娜
that is a monitoring technology and I
那是一种监控技术，我
did not set that up that is actually
没有设置那实际上是
being provided and included in the ECU
被提供并包含在ECU中
installation so what we gonna have we
安装，所以我们会拥有我们
have some dashboards here that are
这里有一些仪表板
actually available and that are already
实际可用，并且已经
well activated for my services so we
为我的服务很好地激活了，所以我们
have a coffee-shop service here again I
我又在这里有咖啡店服务
did not configure that that uses an auto
没有配置使用自动
discovery M inside the technology and
在技​​术内发现M
now I don't know about you but I think
现在我不认识你，但我想
we need some more coffee so what I'm
我们需要更多的咖啡，所以我
gonna do I'm gonna create some new
我要去创造一些新的
coffee create some new coffee create
咖啡创建一些新的咖啡
some more new coffee your coffee new
再来点新咖啡你的新咖啡
coffee new coffee just to have some more
咖啡新咖啡只是为了多喝点咖啡
traffic in our system and now all I'm
系统中的流量，现在我
gonna see a little bit more in my coffee
会在我的咖啡中看到更多
shop so I see that this coffee shop
店，所以我看到这家咖啡店
service actually has now some traffic so
服务实际上现在有一些流量，所以
it includes some default as some
它包括一些默认值
technical metrics out-of-the-box for
开箱即用的技术指标
example what is the request volume what
示例请求量是多少
is the request and duration for that
是该请求和持续时间
specific service and when we look at the
具体服务以及当我们查看
barista service we also see that and we
咖啡师服务，我们也看到了这一点，我们
now actually have some traffic in coming
现在实际上有一些流量
into the system
进入系统
and also we have a look at where the
我们也看看
traffic is coming from and we see o is
流量来自，我们看到o是
actually coming from the coffee shop so
其实是从咖啡店来的
that means that the coffee shop is
这意味着咖啡厅是
indeed calling our service our barista
确实把我们的服务称为咖啡师
service ok
服务还可以
so that is being provided out-of-the-box
这样就可以直接使用
with Cortana with monitoring have
与Cortana一起监控
another nice story that is being
另一个有趣的故事
provided is now a connection it's
现在提供的是它的连接
failing so what I'm gonna do here
失败了，所以我要在这里做什么
actually I'm gonna forward the part off
其实我要把那部分关掉
specific wealth services into the
具体财富服务纳入
cluster so that's action and running on
集群，所以这是行动并在
localhost but that's running inside the
本地主机，但在内部运行
cluster and I'm just using a cute
集群，我只是用一个可爱的
control a port forward command so what
控制端口转发命令
we have here is this cute little guy
我们有一个可爱的小家伙
with the German named Yaga that is a
与德国人Yaga一起
distributed tracing technology and with
分布式跟踪技术以及
that we can trace individual requests
我们可以跟踪单个请求
that go through the system to while
通过系统到
being able to backtrack what's actually
能够回溯实际的情况
going on and which request is going
正在进行，哪个请求正在进行
through which specific instance so if
通过哪个具体实例，如果
you're gonna have a look at that
你要去看看
particular request we're gonna see that
特殊要求，我们将看到
well this is actually this request is
好吧，这实际上是这个请求
going into while the cluster to the
当集群到
ingress ingress gateway and it ends up
入口入口网关，它最终
at the coffee shop application and then
在咖啡店申请，然后
we have another request that
我们还有另一个要求
synchronously calls our barista
同步致电我们的咖啡师
application with for example a request
带有请求的应用程序
that we already know if we had a look at
我们已经知道如果我们看看
the code it should be put request to
应放置在请求中的代码
that URL so now we see that this is
该URL，所以现在我们看到这是
actually being called and we see that
实际上被称为，我们看到
the coffee shop is actually calling that
咖啡店实际上是在打电话
instance of the barista service so we
咖啡师服务的实例，所以我们
can backtrack what's going on inside our
可以回溯我们内部发生的事情
system another interesting technology is
系统另一个有趣的技术是
this one that is called key ally key
这个被称为关键盟友的钥匙
ally is a service graph technology plus
盟友是服务图技术加上
a bunch of other things that actually
一堆实际上是
knows about the history of configuration
了解配置历史
so it's aware of what's going on here
所以它知道这里发生了什么
and let's have to fancy animation here
让我们在这里看动画
and what we see we're gonna see all the
我们所看到的我们将看到所有
sto resources here for example a coffee
在这里存储资源，例如咖啡
shop service and the barista service and
商店服务和咖啡师服务以及
while which one in which particular
而其中哪一个特别
version what that is explaining in a
版本说明了
second is calling which so this has has
第二个是打电话给这个
a look at the actual requests that go
看看实际的要求
through the system
通过系统
and builds up the dependency graph of
并建立
our micro services which well quite
我们的微服务相当不错
frankly is pretty much boring since we
坦率地说，因为我们
only have two applications one calls the
只有两个应用程序，一个调用
other but if you can imagine if we had a
其他，但如果你能想象我们是否有一个
more complex setup here then we actually
更复杂的设置，然后我们实际上
see which version is calling which
查看哪个版本正在调用哪个版本
application so now how does that work
应用程序，现在如何工作
especially that observability being
特别是可观察性
provided out of the box so in a service
提供开箱即用的服务
mesh technology or in Istria
网格技术或在Istria中
specifically what we have is we have our
特别是我们拥有的是
services of kubernetes services and our
kubernetes服务以及我们的服务
deployments that are well running
运行良好的部署
instances running pods but now what we
实例运行Pod，但现在我们
do instead of only having the main
而不是只拥有主要
container we actually have a second
容器我们实际上有第二个
container so called sidecar container a
所谓的边车集装箱
proxy container and actually if we call
代理容器，实际上，如果我们调用
a service for example the coffee shop
服务，例如咖啡店
our request actually ends up at the
我们的请求实际上最终在
proxy container and then we'll or might
代理容器，然后我们将或可能
forward our request to the main
将我们的请求转发给主要
container and then if the main container
容器，然后如果主容器
if our application wants to access
如果我们的应用程序要访问
another service well it accesses that
另一个服务很好，它访问
also through the proxy and that request
也通过代理和那个请求
ends up at the another proxy that again
结束于另一个代理
forwards it to the main container of the
将其转发到
barista instance and the whole thing
咖啡师实例和整个事情
back
背部
and these sidecar containers are
这些边柜是
deployed in each and every pot if we
如果我们部署在每个锅里
have multiple parts parts either each
每个都有多个零件
and one of them would have its own proxy
其中一个将拥有自己的代理
so this is also why if we have a look at
所以这也是为什么如果我们看看
the parts you see that we actually have
您看到的实际上是我们拥有的部分
two containers in each and every part
每个部分有两个容器
two already and they are running and
已经有两个，他们正在运行，
this is well also being provided after
这也可以在以后提供
box I did not specify two containers I
框我没有指定两个容器
already specified one each but this is
每个已经指定一个，但这是
being injected by a steel and now you
被钢注入，现在你
can imagine well how all of that
可以很好地想象所有这些
observability works because well now the
可观察性行之有效，因为现在
proxy sees all of the communication here
代理在这里看到所有通信
and has the ability to emit that
并有能力发出
information for example to Prometheus
信息，例如普罗米修斯
and core fauna or to Yaga and key ally
和核心动物区系，或是Yaga和主要盟友
and so on and so forth there is another
依此类推，还有另一个
thing to be done
要做的事情
- card ee or in our application actually
-卡ee或实际上在我们的应用程序中
if we want to make that work because
如果我们想做那个工作，因为
well if you have a look or if you
好吧，如果您看一下，或者如果您
imagine how that distribute in tracing
想象一下在跟踪中如何分布
technology works specifically how do we
技术特别有效，我们如何
know or how does Yaga know that this
Yaga知道或怎么知道
request is somewhat correlated to these
要求与这些相关
requests well the answer it it doesn't
要求很好的答案，不是
because well just just because that
因为那只是因为
requests coincidentally happened at the
请求恰巧发生在
same time as the other requests that
与其他请求同时
doesn't mean that one caused the other
并不意味着一个引起了另一个
but what we have to do actually is to
但实际上我们要做的是
provide correlation IDs typically an
提供相关ID，通常是
HTTP header information and this is
HTTP标头信息，这是
actually what we have to do manually so
实际上我们必须手动执行
Jager or Zipkin introduces a de facto
Jager或Zipkin引入了事实
standard open Zipkin or open tracing
标准开放Zipkin或开放跟踪
where we had to pass HTTP headers
我们必须传递HTTP标头的地方
they're typically called X - B 3 - tres
他们通常被称为X-B 3-tres
ad span ID and so on and so forth you
广告范围ID等，依此类推
might have seen them before when we need
可能在我们需要之前见过他们
to pass them in our synchronous requests
在我们的同步请求中传递它们
that actually goes through our
这实际上经历了我们
application because we have our orders
申请，因为我们有订单
resource here and if we create a new
资源，如果我们创建一个新的
coffee order and we're gonna end up at
咖啡订单，我们最终会在
this resource and then sto injects these
这种资源，然后注入这些
HTTP headers for us but that means that
我们的HTTP标头，但这意味着
now inside our application we knew would
现在在我们的应用程序中，我们知道会
need to take these HTTP headers pass
需要通过这些HTTP标头
them here in the next call pass them
他们在下一个电话中传递给他们
here into the HTTP client pass them here
这里进入HTTP客户端将它们传递给这里
or actually pass them in here and then
或实际上将它们传递给
extract the HTTP header information
提取HTTP标头信息
again - well put that to DHCP client
再次-将其放到DHCP客户端
because that's a synchronous request
因为那是一个同步请求
right well that works but this will be
很好，那行得通，但这将是
actually pretty cumbersome so we don't
其实很麻烦，所以我们不
want to do that what we can do luckily
想要做到这一点，我们可以幸运地做
is well use another project that is
很好地使用另一个项目是
being provided by micro profile that is
由微型配置文件提供
called micro profile open tracing and
称为微型配置文件公开跟踪和
now if you have a look at my specific
现在，如果你看看我的具体
maiden project here I don't even
我的处女项目我什至没有
introduce that API
介绍该API
why I only used Java eight api's plus
为什么我只使用Java八个api加号
mica profile config plus actually health
云母配置文件配置加上实际运行状况
check this is due to the kubernetes
检查这是由于kubernetes
health checks that we're gonna introduce
我们要介绍的健康检查
but not the micro profile open tracing
但不是微个人资料公开跟踪
why well because we don't even use the
为什么会这样，因为我们什至不使用
API but what we can do is to instruct
API，但我们能做的就是指导
our runtime in this case open Liberty to
在这种情况下，我们的运行时将Liberty打开
please provide this functionality to use
请提供此功能以供使用
the tracing headers and pass them out of
跟踪头并将其传递出去
the box automatically to any a should be
自动将任何一个框
client how does it work
客户如何运作
so this is now a Liberty specific and
所以现在这是针对自由的
what I'm doing here is I configured my
我在这里做的是我配置了
running Liberty with these features that
通过这些功能运行Liberty
I can use so this is now the a little
我可以使用，所以现在有点
bit optimized version that is a little
有点优化的版本
bit more verbose I can say okay I use
我可以说再详细一点
specifically these features here in my
特别是这些功能在我的
running runtime so that is optimizing my
运行运行时，以便优化我的
runtime a little bit and what is the
运行时有点，什么是
interesting part here is actually these
有趣的部分实际上是这些
mica profile open tracing and while a
云母简介打开跟踪，而
Liberty specific Zipkin implementation
自由特定的Zipkin实施
of that what does these things to do
这些是做什么的
well these things actually enable me
这些东西使我真正受益
that if I get a request into the system
如果我收到系统请求
that has these open tracing headers
具有这些开放的跟踪标头
available then well actually I can pass
可用，那么实际上我可以通过
them here and if I end up in a
他们在这里，如果我最终在
synchronous requests in a HTTP client in
HTTP客户端中的同步请求
a jax-rs client then it will
一个jax-rs客户程序，它将
automatically pass these headers in my
自动将这些标头传递给我
request and I don't have to do anything
请求，我不必做任何事情
else I just have to instruct to runtime
否则我只需要指示运行时
that this is actually part of the
这实际上是
application and this will work and it
应用程序，这将工作，它
works because while we see that this
之所以有效，是因为虽然我们看到这
actually connects to the other and
实际上连接到另一个
correlates to the other requests so this
与其他请求相关，因此
is shown in this particular one page and
显示在这一特定页面中，
that one request causes the other that's
一个请求导致另一个
what we need to add for the tracing
我们需要为跟踪添加什么
example here other than that we can see
除了这里的例子，我们可以看到
that the service mesh well provides all
服务网格可以很好地提供所有
this information and then further how
这些信息，然后进一步
that works is we're gonna have a control
可行的是我们将拥有控制权
plane that consists of multiple
由多个组成的平面
components that's provided by pi by by
pi由by提供的组件
the sto insulation
绝缘
and that control plan actually
而那个控制计划实际上
communicates with all of the individual
与所有人沟通
proxy containers so then we can well
代理容器，这样我们就可以
configure of the proxy containers how
配置代理容器的方式
they actually should behave and also we
他们实际上应该表现出来，而且我们
can scrape all of the telemetry data to
可以将所有遥测数据抓取到
provide that observability all right
提供可观察性
that's to be said about the
那是关于
observability part what else we can do
可观察性部分我们还能做什么
in is do actually is well to have some
实际上是有一些
more at advanced networking or some more
更多有关高级联网的信息或更多信息
traffic management because we have these
交通管理，因为我们有这些
proxy and proxy containers being
代理和代理容器
available so now we could actually say
可用，所以我们现在可以说
well instead of routing to this barista
好吧，而不是路由到这个咖啡师
instance for some reason route to
实例出于某种原因转至
something else or provide some more
其他或提供更多
resiliency here so the proxy has now
弹性，所以代理现在
more control over this so let's start
对此有更多控制，让我们开始吧
with some more advanced traffic
有一些更先进的流量
management so this is a fun part let me
管理，这是一个有趣的部分，让我
quickly show you some sto resources this
快速向您展示一些资源
is now a lot of content here and I
现在在这里我有很多内容
provide am will provide you some further
提供我会为您提供更多
resources where I can actually read and
我可以实际阅读和阅读的资源
watch that and a little bit more than
观看，还有一点
one hour but just as an introduction
一个小时，但只是一个介绍
what we have in order to configure the
我们为了配置
traffic management in is do is we have
交通管理是我们要做的
some more llamo yay especially some
一些更多的骆驼，尤其是一些
resources that very much look like
非常像的资源
humanities resources and actually these
人文资源，实际上是这些
are criminales extensions so one type is
是罪犯的扩展名，所以一种是
called virtual service and another one
称为虚拟服务，另一个
is called destination pool so what are
被称为目标池，所以
these a virtual service is well
这些虚拟服务很好
configures a service that is part of the
配置服务的一部分
service mesh in repair with regards to
维修服务网关于
traffic routing so it configures the
流量路由，以便它配置
routing rules for in this case the
在这种情况下的路由规则
barista service and what is this what is
咖啡师服务，这是什么？
the service in the service mesh well per
服务网格中的服务
default all of the kubernetes services
默认所有kubernetes服务
are actually sto service mesh services
实际上是服务网格服务
as well but also we could have some more
以及我们还可以有更多
advanced examples for example we could
例如高级示例，我们可以
provide wild card virtual services arm
提供通配符虚拟服务部门
or extend our a mesh with services that
或通过服务扩展我们的网格
are not actually part of our kubernetes
实际上不是我们的kubernetes的一部分
cluster as
群集为
is called virtual service and we can
被称为虚拟服务，我们可以
provide some routing in this case all of
在这种情况下，提供一些路由
the HTTP routes everything that is
HTTP路由所有的
routing to barista host please wrote to
路由到咖啡师主持人，请写信给
the barista back-end so that's very
咖啡师后端，所以非常
boring that's actually a default route
无聊实际上是默认路线
here and we have this destination rule
在这里，我们有这个目的地规则
that configures further policies for a
可以为
specific destination for a baristas
咖啡师的特定目的地
destination for example if we want to
例如目的地，如果我们想
have some further authorization or some
有一些进一步的授权或一些
mutual TLS that we can also do in this
我们也可以在其中执行双向TLS
deal we could provide that here and it
交易我们可以在这里提供它
also provides the subsets what is a
还提供了子集是什么
subset a subset is a further
子集是一个子集
well sub setting of a specific service
特定服务的细分设置
where we could divide a specific service
我们可以划分特定服务的地方
to multiple slightly different instances
到多个略有不同的实例
so we have only one subset here that is
所以我们这里只有一个子集
actually called v1 and it selects all of
实际上称为v1，它会选择所有
these instances here by a specific label
这些实例在此处带有特定标签
you might have seen that before this
您可能在此之前已经看到
label is actually being provided in the
标签实际上是在
pots so this is another meter
盆，所以这是另一米
information - I'll select some
信息-我将选择一些
information here out-of-the-box it
开箱即用的信息
doesn't do anything because we always
什么也没做，因为我们总是
route to that label but we could specify
路由到该标签，但我们可以指定
that further how the coffee shop looks
那咖啡店的样子
like is very similar you have a virtual
就像很相似，你有一个虚拟的
service and a destination rule as well
服务和目的地规则
and since that is also the user facing
由于那也是用户所面对的
application we have something that is
应用程序，我们有一些东西
called gateway if you're familiar with
如果您熟悉，则称为网关
kubernetes ingresses this is actually
kubernetes进入这实际上是
very similar this provides the ingress
非常相似，这提供了入口
traffic in into the service mesh why we
进入服务网格的原因
use a gateway a while because this is
暂时使用网关，因为这是
aware of the is geo configuration here
知道这里是地理配置
and this then already can use the
然后就可以使用了
correct resources and proxies here and
在此处更正资源和代理，以及
we're gonna route well also everything
我们也会很好地路由一切
to the v1 subset all right now if we
如果我们现在将v1子集
want to have a little bit of a further
想要进一步
configuration here what we could do
在这里配置我们可以做什么
actually is well provide another subset
实际上很好地提供了另一个子集
just for fun that we call me too now
只是为了好玩，我们现在也叫我
let's live code some llamo let's be
让我们现场编码一些llamo
brave here and
在这里勇敢
that works actually I now enhanced my
那实际上有效，我现在增强了我的
subset of the coffee shop service to
咖啡店服务的一部分
include b2 as well you might have seen
可能还包括b2
that before I actually have v2 example
在我实际拥有v2示例之前
here that well uses a different tack a
这里很好地使用了不同的方法
different image here that works slightly
不同的图像在这里稍微起作用
differently and what we could do well
不同的是，我们可以做的很好
for example we could switch that traffic
例如我们可以切换流量
to use the v2 subset instead instead of
使用v2子集代替
people every one subset so what we can
人们每个子集，所以我们可以
do here we can apply this now the nice
这样做我们可以立即应用
story about that is since these
关于这个的故事是因为这些
resources extend kubernetes the issue of
资源扩展了kubernetes的问题
resources or they can see here we can
资源，或者他们可以在这里看到我们可以
actually use cube control to well use
实际使用多维数据集控件来很好地使用
the same resources in the same look and
相同外观的相同资源，
feel so for example cube control get
感觉例如多维数据集控件得到
services gives us the services and queue
服务给我们服务和排队
control at virtual services gives us
虚拟服务的控制使我们
these virtual services this does not
这些虚拟服务不
work in a standalone kubernetes cluster
在独立的kubernetes集群中工作
but it works once we install is to
但是一旦我们安装了它就可以工作
because it extends our API so we can use
因为它扩展了我们的API，所以我们可以使用
the same look and feel which is very
相同的外观和感觉
nice for the development or user
非常适合开发人员或用户
experience and now if we ask for the
经验，现在，如果我们要求
coffee orders again now this is actually
咖啡订单再次，这实际上是
empty why well now because we use the
空，为什么现在好，因为我们使用
other application and per default we
其他应用程序，默认情况下，我们
don't have any orders in the system so
系统中没有任何订单，因此
let's change this we create another
让我们更改它，我们创建另一个
coffee order and now we actually see
咖啡订单，现在我们实际上看到了
that the routing goes to a different
路由选择不同
application to a v2 application that
应用程序到v2应用程序
well has a different response here so we
这里有不同的反应，所以我们
introduce some hypermedia link instead
引入一些超媒体链接
of just the ID if you mem remember it
记住ID的话
from before so this is now to reroute
从以前开始，所以现在要重新路由
the traffic from subset v1 to v2 but
从子集v1到v2的流量，但是
manually or explicitly not only done by
手动或明确地不仅由
kubernetes deployment what we could do
kubernetes部署我们能做什么
also so for example what we can do here
同样，例如我们可以在这里做什么
is to provide some more
是提供更多
well advanced scenarios so instead of
先进的方案，所以代替
having one destination we might say well
有一个目的地，我们可能会说得很好
we want to have two destinations v1 with
我们想要有两个目的地v1
maybe 70% of the traffic and we - with
也许有70％的流量，我们-
30% of the traffic so this is how we
30％的流量，这就是我们的方式
could implement some a be testing for
可以实施一些测试
example that means we deploy to specific
这个例子意味着我们部署到特定的
versions of our application and now we
版本的应用程序，现在我们
instruct the ISTE of proxies actually -
实际指导代理的ISTE-
well do a split traffic routing with a
做好与
percentage base based routing here so if
基于百分比的路由在这里，如果
we say let's do this again not only
我们说我们不仅要再做一次
create it but let's let's ask for the
创建它，但让我们要求
coffee orders so either we get well the
咖啡订单，所以我们要么会好起来
full response with all of the orders
所有订单的全程回应
being created before or well this
在此之前或之前创建
responds with with a new application
用新的应用程序响应
with the v2 application so this is how
使用v2应用程序，这就是方法
we could implement a be testing here and
我们可以在这里实施be测试
canary releases so for example if we
金丝雀发布，例如，如果我们
have a new version and we only want to
有一个新版本，我们只想
sprout a specific subset of here our
在这里发芽我们的特定子集
users to introduce a change not in a big
用户介绍的变化不大
bang way but for example introduced only
爆炸的方式，但仅举例说明
5% of the traffic first or 10:30 and so
流量的5％或10:30等
on and so forth and gradually increase
依此类推，然后逐渐增加
that this helps us a lot in doing so and
这样做对我们有很大帮助
we can we can do that here actually in
我们可以在这里实际做到
an automated way so what else is there
自动化的方式，还有什么
we could have some other approach where
我们可以有其他方法
we do some a be testing as well where we
我们也在我们进行一些测试
said okay instead of that we actually
说好吧，而不是我们实际上
introduced some further criteria for
介绍了一些进一步的标准
example saying instead of the route
例如说而不是路线
match the traffic for example match the
匹配流量，例如匹配
HTTP headers to think this is an array -
HTTP标头认为这是一个数组-
for example take the the header Pete
例如带标题Pete
I think it's named user-agent no it's no
我认为它被命名为用户代理，不是
headers user-agent that's that's name
标头用户代理，即名称
and then having a rag X for example I
然后以抹布X为例
think this is the default example to
认为这是默认示例
route the Firefox here Firefox browser
在此处路由Firefox浏览器
to this route v2 and the rest goes to v1
前往这条路线v2，其余前往v1
I hope this routing was correct
我希望这个路由是正确的
again this is a llamo live coding
再次，这是llamo现场编码
oh this was not correct the error
哦，这是不正确的错误
headers use an agent this correct nope
标头使用代理，此正确无误
so this is why I should not do live
所以这就是为什么我不应该活
coding with the mo I guess I need to
我想我需要用mo编码
actually have a look at how that looks
看看那个样子
like you use an agent action route
就像您使用座席行动路线
oh this was correct yeah first one is in
哦，这是正确的，是的，第一个在
the array second one isn't again live
数组第二个不再存在
coding but now what we can see that if
编码，但是现在我们可以看到
we ask for our coffee orders then now we
我们要求我们的咖啡订单，那么现在我们
always get that version v1 unless we
始终获得该版本v1，除非我们
specify in this case an HTTP header user
在这种情况下指定HTTP标头用户
agent or well we actually use the
代理商或我们实际上使用
Firefox browser and then we all only get
Firefox浏览器，然后我们所有人都只能得到
this resource so this is again for
这个资源，所以这又是为了
further a be testing to route a specific
进一步测试以路由特定的
subset of your users to to that resource
该资源的部分用户
for example so let's undo this again
例如，让我们再次撤消此操作
let's route everything to we won again
让我们将一切路由到我们再次赢得
and applied so this is how to introduce
并应用，所以这是如何介绍
some further advanced traffic management
一些进一步的高级流量管理
what I also include here and will
我在这里也将包括的内容
provide us some code is actually some
给我们一些代码实际上是一些
example what it can do connect canary
示例它可以做什么连接金丝雀
release with a more automated approach
以更自动化的方式发布
so what you should do of course as part
因此，您当然应该做的一部分
of your continuous deployment pipeline
您的连续部署流程
or as as part of your deployments
或作为您部署的一部分
is not do that in a manual way like I
不是像我这样以手动方式
just did by manually editing llamo but
只是通过手动编辑llamo而完成的，
actually to provide some automation
实际上提供一些自动化
where you make this part of your
你把这部分变成你的
deployment to say okay we have a new
部署说好，我们有一个新
deployment here that means we have a new
在这里部署意味着我们有了一个新的
version of coffee shop or barista for
咖啡店或咖啡师的版本
example and how we deploy that is not in
示例以及我们如何部署该示例
a Big Bang approach but in order to set
大爆炸的方法，但为了设定
up a new version of barista and use is
新版本的咖啡师并使用
do to gradually increase the traffic
逐步增加流量
routing from let's say 1% to 5% to 25%
从1％路由到5％到25％
to whatever you want to specify and then
到您要指定的任何内容，然后
use also the provided monitoring to see
也使用提供的监控来查看
whether the new version immediately
是否立即更新新版本
blows up and produces a lot of errors
炸毁并产生很多错误
and then automatically roll back if
然后自动回滚
that's the case or you can roll out
就是这种情况，或者您可以推出
further and increase that that traffic
进一步增加流量
to will not affect that many users is if
不会影响那么多用户，如果
something goes wrong and to make an to
出问题了，要
have a better automated approach of your
有一个更好的自动化方法
deployment so that is an approach and
部署，这是一种方法，
that you should take what I told you
你应该接受我告诉你的
before is that we also have some
之前是我们也有一些
resiliency being built in so what we can
内建弹性，我们可以
do actually is to say well what happens
其实要做的就是说好
if the baristas service actually goes
如果咖啡师服务真的去了
down and becomes unavailable how does
下来，变得不可用怎么办
our application react if that is not
如果不是这样，我们的应用程序会做出反应
there so if you had a look at the
在那里，如果你看看
barista HCP client here is that well we
我们的咖啡师HCP客户很好
use the HTTP client with the timeout
将HTTP客户端与超时一起使用
which is always a good idea
这总是一个好主意
so we specify that time of behavior here
所以我们在这里指定行为的时间
but what if we were using some
但是如果我们使用一些
technology that where that is not the
技术，那不是
case or what if well that is not
情况或如果不是这样
supported or being specified well
得到很好的支持或指定
actually in this case we can also use
实际上在这种情况下，我们也可以使用
some for example timeout behavior in our
例如我们的超时行为
proxies by the SEO configuration so what
通过SEO配置代理什么
we can do actually is to provide while a
我们实际上可以做的是提供
timeout definition for example with one
超时定义，例如一个
second that is part of this route here
第二个是这条路线的一部分
and that is being provided in our
而这是在我们的
virtual service routing so if we apply
虚拟服务路由，因此如果我们应用
that well this means then while we have
那意味着当我们有
a timeout being applied
正在应用超时
and now if we well create a coffee
现在，如果我们很好地煮咖啡
orders that is guarded by a timeout I
超时保护的订单
guess well does it work I guess it looks
我猜它看起来很好吗
like it right well how do we test it
很好喜欢我们如何测试它
whether that timeout is actually being
那个超时是否真的在
applied because that route now is
之所以应用，是因为该路线现在是
guarded by one second timeout so that
由一秒钟的超时保护
means if that would take longer or if
意味着是否需要更长的时间，或者
the barista application is unavailable
咖啡师应用程序不可用
then this will kill the connection after
然后这将终止连接
one second but in order to test that we
一秒钟，但为了测试我们
would either need to redeploy a fault
要么需要重新部署故障
test version of our barista application
咖啡师应用程序的测试版本
in order to test it well that works
为了对其进行良好的测试
right always test whether that is
正确地测试是否
actually the case or we use well some
实际情况还是我们很好地使用了一些
behavior Byam some functionality but is
行为Byam有一些功能，但是
do that actually can do that so for
这样做实际上可以做到
testing purposes we can actually
测试目的，我们实际上可以
introduce some faults so that means just
引入一些错误，这意味着
for fun we can actually instruct the
为了好玩，我们实际上可以指示
barista service to well throw some
咖啡师服务好丢一些
arrows or make the applicator make the
箭头或使涂药器
connection slower so what we can do is
连接速度较慢，所以我们可以做的是
actually to introduce some faults for
实际上引入一些缺陷
example some delay let's say we want to
例如一些延迟，假设我们要
have a fixed delay of three seconds but
固定延迟三秒，但
not all the time and only in the 50% of
并非一直如此，仅在
the cases so now for testing purposes
现在的情况用于测试
don't do that in production this will
不要在生产中这样做
make the application slower in order to
使应用程序变慢，以便
test the behavior off well our
测试我们的行为
application or of well the environment
应用或良好的环境
here so what happens is that now either
这里发生了什么
that request immediately works or the
该请求立即生效，或者
briefs application that is called in a
在一个中调用的摘要应用程序
synchronous way would take three seconds
同步方式需要三秒钟
which is actually too long for the
实际上对于
timeout and then we get a timeout after
超时，然后我们超时
a while one second that is being
一会儿
provided here and then we also see well
提供在这里，然后我们也很好看
that we have a fault request if we have
如果我们有一个错误请求
a look at our let's try to find a faulty
看看我们让我们尝试找出有问题的地方
request here in our distributed tracing
在我们的分布式跟踪中请求此处
with the Yaga for example
以Yaga为例
so I can find one right now depending on
所以我现在可以根据找到一个
how much we trace here so that would be
我们在这里追踪了多少
a variable here and if we had a look at
一个变量，如果我们看一下
one particular request that is actually
实际上是一个特定的请求
being aborted after one second or where
一秒钟或之后被终止
we also see it so this is now actually
我们也看到了，所以这实际上是
more interesting the key ally
更有趣的关键盟友
observability the service graph now
现在可观察的服务图
provides us some more details so before
向我们提供了更多详细信息，因此在此之前
we had v1 and v2 so that is now
我们有v1和v2，所以现在
available since it knows about the
可用，因为它知道
subsets and it would show while we're
子集，它会在我们处于
we're routing to and before we were
我们要去之前和之前
actually routing to both versions now we
现在实际路由到两个版本
only route to v1 but we see that this is
仅路由到v1，但我们看到这是
not while fully a functional that we get
当我们完全获得功能时
a specific error I'm great
我很棒的特定错误
here calculated over the last time so
这里是上次计算得出的
that again provides some more
再次提供更多
observability what's going on here same
可观察性这是怎么回事
with Cortana what we what we see and the
与Cortana一起，我们所看到的以及
coffee-shop application the success rate
咖啡店申请成功率
goes down and so on and so forth so that
下去等等，这样
provides you some information out of the
为您提供一些信息
box so this is also helpful for
框，因此对
debugging and testing purposes in
调试和测试目的
general if you want to test how your
一般，如果您想测试您的
application reacts once an an external
应用程序一旦外部响应
system is faulty then you can have a
系统有问题，那么您可以
look at that as well what is also very
看看那个也很
helpful so just quickly the last thing
有用的，所以很快就做最后一件事
is well how to debug your java
很好如何调试Java
enterprise applications in kubernetes
Kubernetes中的企业应用程序
environment so there are a few tools
环境，所以有一些工具
available that actually help you or to
可以实际帮助您或
debug what's going on here and
调试这里发生的事情并
specifically what I want to show you is
我想告诉你的是
two things is one tool called watch and
两件事是一种叫做监视的工具，
deploy or wad made by Adam bean which
由亚当豆制成的
well does not much and actually listen
好，并不多，实际上听
for any file changes and rebuilds and
对于任何文件更改和重建，以及
redeploy your application into a thin a
将您的应用程序重新部署到精简版
deployment artifact same thing what we
部署工件相同的东西我们
have here and what you can also do well
在这里，你也可以做得很好
if you point watts to a deployment and
如果您将瓦数用于部署，并且
directory that is actually being being
实际存在的目录
connected to a running container you can
连接到正在运行的容器，您可以
how to redeploy your docker containers
如何重新部署您的Docker容器
as well not just local applique
不仅是本地贴花
well but now we also have kubernetes so
好吧，但现在我们也有kubernetes，所以
that works I provided some information
可以，我提供了一些信息
if you want to look at Hanna have a look
如果你想看看汉娜看看
at that how that works with local docker
那与本地码头工人如何工作
containers we're using what what it also
容器，我们也使用什么
works well using kubernetes cluster if
如果使用kubernetes集群可以很好地工作
you use a tool called at telepresence so
您使用称为网真的工具
that is a tool to well connect and
那是一个很好的连接工具
replace um containers that run in a
替换在
kubernetes environment with your local
本地的kubernetes环境
processes or local running containers so
进程或本地正在运行的容器
what that is it well introduces a two
那是什么好介绍了两个
way proxy where you're actually
方式代理您实际所在的位置
providing an instance for running
提供运行实例
service such as coffee shop where you
咖啡店等服务
then well actually provide that service
然后很好地提供该服务
with something that runs on your local
在你本地运行的东西
laptop just for testing purposes you can
笔记本电脑仅用于测试目的，您可以
connect into the cluster and use the
连接到集群并使用
same while networking features for
相同的联网功能
example the dns resolution that I showed
我显示的dns分辨率示例
you before and if you use such a tool
您之前以及是否使用过这样的工具
suggest this watch and deploy tool you
向您建议此监视和部署工具
can even hot and hot reload your code
甚至可以热重新加载代码
have code changes here and have them
在这里进行代码更改并进行更改
being reflected in your application so
反映在您的应用程序中
for example if we provide this orders
例如，如果我们提供此订单
example again we have the coffee orders
再次举例，我们有咖啡订单
here well now we have the time or
现在好了，我们有时间或
example so that takes too long but now
例子，所以花了太长时间，但是现在
we see ok new application no orders in
我们看到ok新应用没有订单
the system and what is now here is that
系统，现在这里是
this is actually being replaced and then
这实际上是被取代，然后
locally we have well a running coffee
在当地，我们有杯咖啡
shop container and if we access our
购买集装箱，如果我们访问我们的
application here we actually end up at a
应用在这里，我们实际上最终以
local running container and what we can
本地运行的容器以及我们可以做什么
do then is actually change something in
然后要做的实际上是改变某些东西
our application for example say well
我们的应用程序说的很好
instead of just providing the order here
而不是只在这里提供订单
also provide some let's say the location
还提供一些假设的位置
that I just showed you before so we want
我刚才给你看过的，所以我们想要
to enhance this to introduce and the
加强介绍和
location into our order as well and now
位置以及我们现在的位置
what that is doing is actually
这实际上是在做
rebuilding our replication and then
重建我们的复制，然后
immediately redeploy
立即重新部署
and especially if you use an application
特别是如果您使用应用程序
server that can redeploy quickly that
可以快速重新部署的服务器
means your changes are automatically
表示您的更改是自动的
reflected okay well now you don't see
反映好吧，现在你看不到
anything because we have to create an
任何事情，因为我们必须创建一个
order first but then you see well now
先点菜，然后你现在看得很好
also in the orders resource this
也在订单资源中
location is being provided case in Java
Java中提供位置的情况
and again we could change and redeploy
再一次，我们可以改变并重新部署
it or introduce some some other examples
或介绍一些其他示例
and immediately you would have you
立刻你就会拥有你
change available that is actually in
实际存在的可用更改
only in your running and docker
仅在您的运行和泊坞窗中
container or locally but very quickly
容器或本地，但很快
you see it very quickly redeploys and if
您会很快看到它重新部署，如果
you use the tools such as telepresence
您使用网真之类的工具
you can actually connect that into your
您实际上可以将其连接到您的
local development to your local
本地发展到本地
kubernetes cluster for development
kubernetes集群开发
purposes and to debug or develop your
目的并调试或开发您的
applications connecting to them and well
应用程序连接到他们以及
give up them locally in the local
在当地放弃他们
container if you need to or use such a
容器，如果您需要或使用这样的
tool to improve your development
改善您的发展的工具
productivity so that's another way to
生产力，这是另一种方式
well introduce some further for the
好介绍一些
productivity enhancement for your
为您提高生产力
Jakarta EE application inside a
Jakarta EE应用程序内部
kubernetes environment so if you take
kubernetes环境，所以如果您采取
aways for container orchestration or
进行容器编排或
kubernetes em in general what it
kubernetes em一般是什么
provides us is well a few things for
为我们提供了一些东西
example we have some service discovery
例如我们有一些服务发现
provided we saw that in the barista
只要我们在咖啡师那里看到
application we have some dns resolution
应用我们有一些DNS解析
being there out-of-the-box and the
开箱即用
services specifically distribute our
服务专门分发我们的
load and do some load balancing over the
加载并在
multiple instances we might specify and
我们可能会指定多个实例，
of course kubernetes also sets up all
当然kubernetes也会设置所有
the complicated networking and
复杂的网络和
configuration of our applications so we
配置我们的应用程序，所以我们
don't have to do that in our application
不必在我们的应用程序中这样做
also we have some deployment and
我们也有一些部署
scalability options we can deploy a new
可扩展性选项，我们可以部署新的
version with zero downtime we can scale
停机时间为零的版本，我们可以扩展
up and down having one replicas two
上下有一个副本两个
replicas ten in a very simple way and
以非常简单的方式复制十个
declarative approach what service
声明式方法什么服务
masters provide is they further that add
主人提供的是他们进一步增加
some cross-cutting concerns to our
我们的一些横切关注点
services in a transparent way that means
以透明的方式提供服务，这意味着
without changing
不变
applications so concerns such as
诸如此类的应用
resiliency and traffic management
弹性和流量管理
observability authentication
可观察性认证
authorization and so on and so forth and
授权等等。
specifically what I like about it is it
我特别喜欢的是它
integrates where well with the approach
与方法融为一体
of Java Enterprise so that we don't have
Java Enterprise之所以没有
to well put in all these concerns into
把所有这些问题都纳入
our applications or into the
我们的应用程序或进入
implementations so what we ship actually
实施，所以我们实际运送的是
is still a thin deployment artifact that
仍然是一个精简的部署工件，
well builds and integrates very well
很好地建立和整合
with containers with docker containers
与码头工人容器
thanks to copy and write filesystem
感谢复制和写入文件系统
layers and that means our business logic
层，这意味着我们的业务逻辑
is being provided in the application in
在应用程序中提供
the Java code using Java and Turk our de
使用Java和Turk的Java代码
api's and everything else is then well
api以及其他一切都很好
either being implemented by the
要么由
application runtime by the application
应用程序的应用程序运行时
container here or being part of the
容器在这里或属于
environment in this case then the sto
在这种情况下，那么环境
cluster and the sto sidecar containers
集群和stosidecar容器
so by doing so we can actually focus on
因此，我们实际上可以专注于
what we should focus on as developers
作为开发人员我们应该关注什么
that is implementing business logic so
那就是实现业务逻辑
now if you want some further resources
现在，如果您需要更多资源
or a half you have this example
或一半你有这个例子
available on github with all the code
在github上可用的所有代码
here including some workshop actually
这里实际上包括一些工作坊
that we created where you can go and get
我们创造了可以去的地方
your kubernetes cluster with iste i in
您的isteió在kubernetes集群中
the cloud so you can get that for free
云，所以您可以免费获得它
and try out kubernetes in this do if you
并尝试使用kubernetes，如果您
want we have a lot of resources
希望我们有很多资源
available here we can see coffee shop
在这里可以看到咖啡店
and baristas service create your own
和咖啡师服务创建您自己的
coffee and also well see the
咖啡，也很好看
observability features of is do see how
的可观察性功能是看如何
that integrates with Java EE jacquard EE
与Java EE提花EE集成
and micro profile and have a look at
和微观概况，看看
that if you want so I will provide you
如果您愿意，我会为您提供
all of these links and also how to do
所有这些链接以及操作方法
this a WOD watch and deploy approach
这是WOD监视和部署方法
with docker and with the kubernetes
使用docker和kubernetes
debug example other than that I hope
除了我希望的调试示例
this was a very helpful session for you
这对您来说是非常有帮助的会议
and thanks a lot for your attention
非常感谢您的关注
thanks so much Sebastian for an awesome
非常感谢塞巴斯蒂安的出色
demo and thank you to the community for
演示，感谢社区
coming out and watching it was fantastic
出来看着它真是太棒了
so as Sebastian said he'll be providing
就像塞巴斯蒂安所说，他将提供
links I'll throw them in the description
链接，我将其放入描述中
down below for everybody to access and
下方供所有人访问，
at this time we have no questions so
目前我们没有问题，所以
thank you for joining us and we'll see
感谢您加入我们，我们将会看到
you for our next Jakarta EE Tech Talk
您参加我们的下一次雅加达EE技术讲座
have a good one everyone thank you
大家好，谢谢